[Music]
depression
is a debilitating mental disorder with a
severe impairment to quality of life
the drugs don't work particularly well
have a bunch of side effects so
searching for alternative antidepressant
agents with proper efficacy and safety
is necessary well
there is this green algae called
chlorella that's been used as a dietary
supplement and alternative medicine in
asia for centuries why not put it to the
test a randomized controlled trial of
chlorella in patients with major
depression
subjects were randomized to standard
therapy or standard therapy plus 1800
milligrams of chlorella which is about
three quarters of a teaspoon a day
and
significant improvements in physical and
cognitive symptoms of depression as well
as anxiety
wow
okay but
what word is missing here
a randomized controlled trial of
chlorella
what we want is a randomized
placebo-controlled trial here they
compared chlorella
to nothing
half got some special treatment the
other half got nothing the perfect setup
for the placebo effect especially when
the measured outcomes are mostly just
about how they're subjectively feeling
now you could argue look
that much chlorella would only cost
about 10 cents a day it's healthy for
you anyway and depression is such a
serious disease why not just give it a
try
ok but i'd still like to know if it
actually works or not
this other study on chlorella i
highlighted suffered from a similar
problem but at least had an objective
quantifiable outcome a significant
decrease in liver inflammation
but this study had no control group at
all so maybe they just would have gotten
better on their own for some reason but
there's never been a randomized
double-blind placebo-controlled trial of
chlorella for liver disease
until
now
and not just any liver disease
non-alcoholic fatty liver disease which
thanks to the obesity pandemic now
affects one in four people on earth
let's see if 1200 milligrams of
chlorella a day will help it's about a
half teaspoon closer to just a nickel a
day and
significant drops in liver inflammation
perhaps because they lost significantly
more weight about a pound a week over
the eight weeks which would explain the
significant improvement in fasting blood
sugars they conclude that chlorella has
significant weight reducing effects with
meaningful improvements in liver
function
how about a double-blind randomized
placebo-controlled study of chlorella
for cholesterol compared with the
control group the chlorella group
exhibited remarkable changes in total
cholesterol
wow
how much
only 1.6
what and note they said total
cholesterol if you look at what really
matters ldl cholesterol no effect
whatsoever
thankfully that's not what other studies
found a meta-analysis of 19 randomized
controlled trials of chlorella for
cholesterol involving hundreds of
subjects found that those taking
chlorella did drop their ldl eight
points on average and even drop their
blood pressure a few points
uh four grams or more a day for at least
eight weeks seems to be the magic
formula that would be about two
teaspoons a day that's a lot of
chlorella but if you can find a
palatable way to take it it might help
this is the latest a dietary cholesterol
challenge they had people eat three eggs
a day with without a few spoonfuls of
chlorella
in this double-blind randomized
placebo-controlled study 34 participants
ingested 510 milligrams of dietary
cholesterol from three eggs
concomitantly with a dose of chlorella
or a matched placebo for four weeks
just eating the eggs alone 14 rise in
ldl cholesterol but with the chlorella
significantly less
therefore chlorella can be playing a
useful role in maintaining healthy blood
cholesterol levels
another way
would be to not eat three eggs a day
that reminds me of this other study to
assess the ability of chlorella to
detoxify carcinogenic heterocyclic
amines the cancer-causing chemicals
created when you fry bake broil or
barbecue meat the chlorella did seem to
lower the levels of one of the cooked
meat carcinogens flowing through their
bodies but didn't quite reach
statistical significance
or what about polycyclic aromatic
hydrocarbons another class of
cancer-causing compounds found
particularly in smoked meats cigarettes
includes numerous genotoxic dna damaging
carcinogens
and again chlorella did seem to lower
levels but not significantly so still
if you're gonna
sit down to like ham and eggs for
breakfast or something make sure to add
lots of chlorella and make them green
eggs and ham
[Music]
foreign